A Guide to the Additional Papers of Alan Cheuse, 1991-1995
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional Papers of Alan Cheuse 1991-1995
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10726-n
This collection consists of ca. 300 items (3 Hollinger boxes, 2 linear feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Alan Cheuse of Fairfax, Virginia, placed his papers on loan to the Library on September 20, 1995. The papers were purchased by the Library on September 11, 2003.
Scope and Content Information
These additions to the papers of Alan Cheuse, American novelist and reviewer, ca. 300 items (3 Hollinger boxes, 2 linear feet), 1991-1995, consist of manuscripts of books and short stories by Alan Cheuse, personal and professional correspondence, printed material, invitations to literary events and conferences, book reviews, an appointment book for 1994, two cassette tape recordings, and manuscripts of short stories of other authors to be used on the radio program The Sound of Writing.
Correspondents and topics include: John W. Aldridge, (1994 Jun 26); Elizabeth Arthur, (1995 Jan 11); Barbara Ascher, (1994 Apr 28); Rick Bass, (1995 Mar 25); Charlie Baxter, (1995 Feb 9); Stephen Becker, (1994 Aug 10); Jackson R Bryer,. (1994 Aug 24 and 26, Dec 21); Frederick Busch, (1995 Mar 29); Ron Carlson, (1994 Aug 2); Josephine Carson, (1994 Oct 4); Fred Chappell, (1995 Feb 17); Lee Cullum, (1994 May 13, Jul 19); Madison Davis, J. (1994 Sep 30, Oct 12; 1995 Mar 24); Nicholas Delbanco, (1994 Jun 13 and 30); E.L Doctorow,. (1995 Mar 10); Carolyn Doty, (1995 Jan 22); Robert Drake, (1994 Jul 25, Sep 13; 1995 Jan 20); Stu Dybek, (1994 Nov 17; 1995 Mar 20); Richard Elman, (1994 Sep 30, Dec 27; 1995 Jan 22, Feb 1, Mar 2); Clayton Eshleman, editor of Sulfur (1995 Mar 16); Brian Evenson, (1995 Jan 4 and 28, Feb 13); Michael Flanagan, (1994 Dec 2); Maria Flook, (1995 Feb 6); Laura Furman, (1994 Aug 15); David Galef, (1995 Jan 27); Oakley Hall, (1994 Nov 30); Sam Halpert, (1994 Dec 6); Githa Hariharan, (1994 Jul 12; 1995 Jan ?); Jim Harrison, (1995 Mar 17); Edward Hirsch, (1994 Sep 25); Jim Houston, (1994 Sep 18, Nov 1, Dec 5); Howard Junker, editor of Zyzzyva (1994 Aug 25); David Michael Kaplan, (1995 Mar 2); Bilge Karasu (1994 Nov 2); Karel Kovanda, Representative of the Czech Republic to the United Nations (1995 Jan 16); William Kennedy, (1995 Feb 6); Kathie Lang, editor of Southern Methodist University Press (1994 Jul 20, Oct 14 and 27; 1995 Jan 24 and 26, Mar 14); Barry Lopez, (1994 Nov 1; 1995 Feb 1 and 26); Richard McCann, (1994 Dec 5); Daryl McGrath, (1995 Jan 29); Norman Mailer, (1995 Mar 7); Nordan, Lewis (1995 Feb 25); Cynthia Ozick, (1994 Dec 9); Michael Parker, (1994 Jun 7); Robert Phillips, (1994 Aug 21); Lois Rosenthal, (1994 Aug 29); George A Singer,. (1995 Feb 8 and 27, Mar 27); Gibbs M. Smith, (1994 May 20, Jul 8 and 19; 1995 Mar 23 and 28); Elizabeth Spencer, (1995 Jan 27); Peter Stine, editor of Witness (1994 Jun 24); Kathleen Tyau, (1995 Mar 27); Jon Manchip White, (1995 Feb 15); Tobias Wolff, (1994 Dec 6)
Subjects include: Cliff Jackson and Bill Clinton (1994 Jun 13); Bernard Malamud (1994 Jun 13); Eric Pankey article re transcendence "To Repair the Material of Experience" (see also Cheuse's article in this collection, "Dog Spelled Backward") (1994 Jun 22, Sep 12); "The Mexican Maid" by Alan Cheuse (1994 Jul 18); Rowing in Eden by Alan Cheuse (1994 Jul 20); article by Victor Perera re politics of Guatemala 1994 Sep 22; Paula Gover's White Boys and River Girls back jacket blurb (1994 Nov 1)
Contents List
- SERIES I: TYPED MANUSCRIPTS
  - "An Afternoon of Harp Music in Lake Charles, Louisiana" 1994 (Box 1)
  - "Dog Spelled Backward" for Manoa Symposium n.d. (Box 1)
  - The Grandmothers' Club A Suite of Scenes(Adapted from the novel The Grandmothers' Club) 210 pages n.d. (Box 1)
  - Rabbi Guatemala A Suite of Scenes (Adapted from the novel The Grandmothers' Club) Second Draft, 158 pages 1993 (Box 1)
  - Rabbi Guatemala(Adapted from the novel The Grandmothers' Club) with changes by the author - Theater Workshop, George Mason University, 140 pages 1994 Nov 14 (Box 1)
  - Rowing in Eden Fourth Draft, 444 pages (3 folders) 1993 (Box 1)
  - Rowing in Eden- Incomplete Draft n.d. (Box 2)
  - "The Year in Literature: USA" in The Encyclopedia Britannica[1994] (Box 2)
- SERIES II: CORRESPONDENCE and MISCELLANEOUS FILES
  - Appointment Calendar 1994 (Box 2)
  - Book Reviews 1994 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (4 folders) 1994 Apr-Dec (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (2 folders) 1995 Jan-Mar, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Invitations to Literary Events and Conferences 1994-1995, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Printed Material 1991-1994 (Box 3)
  - Poster advertising a reading given by Alan Cheuse at Muhlenberg College (oversize) [1994?] Sep 21 (Box 3)
  - The Sound of Writing XII and XIII, Programs 131-156 [1994] (Box 3)
  - Short Stories sent to Alan Cheuse for The Sound of Writing programs, including Tom Coraghessan Boyle, John Dufresne, Githa Hariharan, Lewis Nordan, and Joyce Carol Oates, most with a cover letter or card 1995 Feb (Box 3)
  - Recording of Alan Cheuse and Norman Mailer at the Smithsonian (see letter from Jackson R. Bryer (1994 Aug 26) 1994 Apr 19, audio cassette tape recording (Box 3)
  - Recording of All Things Considered, National Public Radio, book recommendations of Alan Cheuse for Christmas gifts 1994 Dec 13, audio cassette tape recording (Box 3)